还给了我钱  让我向她汇报你们的动静
And offered me a bunch of cash to talk behind your back.
按计划行事  是吧?
So we stick to the plan, right?
是啊
Yeah. cool.
我找到一本护照  谁是格雷 米勒?
I found a passport. who's Gary Miller?
我正努力让我们能在一起
I've been working on a way for us to be together.
詹姆斯  你要我还怎么信你?
James, how-how can I believe you?
你要我怎么相信其他事?
Hocan I believe anything anymore?
还有个办法出去?
We got a way out of this?
要弄点东西来支撑隧道
We need some kind of support brace for thtunnel.
- 不然的话呢?  - 一旦倒塌  我们就都被活埋了
Or what? or the whole thing collapses, and we're buried alive.
别再找借口了
No more excuses.
由于这个美国佬  兄弟都死了
Papa's dead because of this yankee.
如果必要  我会亲手宰了他  行吧?
I'll kill him myself if I have to, all right?
他从那蒸笼里活着出来了
He survived the box.
那又如何?
So what?
警卫们都看着斯科菲尔德
The guards went after Scofield.
他赢了
Scofield won.
他都成英雄了
He's a folk hero now.
听着  我和你一样  都想要斯科菲尔德死
Look, I want Scofield dead as much as you,
但绝不能引起造反
But not at the cost of an uprising.
有信件
Mail call.
那是谁?
Who's that?
是我儿子
That's my son.
蒂博格 说行了   机会来了
Bagwell gave the okay. the coast is clear.
走吧
We gotta go.
我以为再见不到你了
I didn't think I'd see you again.
一旦被关进那蒸笼  就...
Once someone goes into the box, it's...
是场误会罢了
It was a misunderstanding.
他们想要你说直升机的事  是吧?
They wanted to talk to you about the helicopters, right?
什么直升机?
What helicopters?
你是真的想要越狱么?
Were you really trying to escape?
我不知道你说什么  你自己也不清楚吧
I don't know what you're talking about, and neither do you.
你也知道了   蒂博格也加入了
Just so you know, Bagwell's coming with us.
那时你走了
You were gone.
而他拥有我们所需要的东西
He had something we needed.
我别无选择
I didn't have a choice.
好吧
Fine.
新计划是怎样的?
So what's the new plan?
你跟他说了么?
Did you tell him?
是的
Yeah.
我加入你们了
I am coming with you.
行了  知道了
Okay by me.
都听到了吧? 你听到了吧 警察兄?
Everyone hear that? you hear that, lawman?
不过你得在这看着
But you're staying up here.
是不是我说的不够清楚啊
Maybe I didn't enunciate myself.
去下面干活需要两只手的
The work downstairs requires two hands.
我们需要有人在这看着  以防萨米回来
Hey. we need somebody to stay outside in case Sammy returns.
我想我们不能从这挖
I thought we couldn't dig through this stuff.
支撑处很危险
The bracing's gonna be tricky.
除非有合适的支撑点
Unless the tunnel gets the proper support,
否则就会全塌下来
It's all going to come down on our heads.
所以我们得弄东西支撑隧道
We should have the materials for the braces,
不过我们需要锯子来切割  还要一个锤子
But we'll need a a saw to cut tto size. and a hammer.
你能弄到么?
Can you help us out?
是的  可以
Yeah. I can do that.
两天时间
Two days.
要是不行呢?
And if not?
两天时间
Two days.
威廉 应该有我们要的东西
Guillermo should have everything we need.
你知道他在哪  是吧?
You know where he is, right?
我想在  呃...
I think it's, uh...
在走廊的左边
It's down this corridor on the left.
在中间   40号房间
Halfway down. cell 40.
走廊那边  左边
Down the corridor on the left.
40号房  行了
Cell 40. okeydoke.
你迷路了么  蒂博格?
Are you lost already, Teodoro?
不
No.
迷路的是你
But you are.
YYeTs人人影视字幕组出品
最新最快字幕下载请登录：www.YYeTs.net
■
字幕：YYeTs人人影视字幕组  后期：梁良
这个房间归我了
This is my room now.
你玩完了
You're done in here.
要是今天你肯做了斯科菲尔德
If you had gone after Scofield today,
那就还值得原谅
All would have been forgiven.
这是在自杀
This is suicide.
闭嘴  老家伙
Shut up, old man!
我倒要试一试
I'll take my chances.
你以为你可以管理索纳?
You think you can run sona?
你连运送东西都办不了
You couldn't even run shipments from one dock to the other,
但是我还一直留着你
But I still keep you by my side.
我会让你走出这扇门
I'll let you walk out of here
让你颜面无存
Out of respect for what you were.
来啊
Come on!
滚出去
Get the hell out of here!
大家都准备好了么?
All of you ready to do this?
在勒齐回来前
Until Lechero gets back,
我们要找些这个
We should start looking for pieces
大约四尺长
About four feet in length.
现在  这里归我管了
I'm running things now!
任何人有意见的话...
Anyone got problem with that...
就过来拿
...come get it!
很好
Good.
第一件事：
First order of business,
谁给我带来迈克·斯科菲尔德  这浪姆酒就归谁
A case of rum to the man who brings me Michael Scofield!
放心
Don't worry.
我们会带齐现钞过来的
We'll be there with all the cash.
行么?  谢谢
Okay? gracias.
奥斯贝托  这就是你要找的人
Osberto. that's who you want to talk to.
这家伙能耐够大么?
This guy on the up-and-up?
我进索纳的事就是他安排的
The guy I was running things into sona for arranged this,
所以这事应该也能办成的
So it's as up as it's gonna get for this kind of deal. so, yes.
不过   奥斯贝托不会说英语
Osberto doesn't speak english, though,
那你准备怎么做?
So how do you want to work it?
我得去见苏珊
I need to meet with Susan.
我会带上索菲亚   她能帮我翻译
I'll take Sofia. she can translate for me.
不用担心
Don't worry about it.
见到苏珊后  你要我怎么说?
So when I meet with Susan, what do you want me to tell her?
她想听什么  你就告诉她什么
Tell her whatever you think she wants to hear.
帮我们尽量争取时间  行么?
Just buy us enough time to do our thing, all right?
一切顺利   兄弟
Home stretch, papi.
兄弟  我不知道怎么感谢你才好
Listen, man. I want to thank you for everything.
- 林肯  拜托  - 回去后 我一定回报你
Oh, linc, please. when we get home, I got your back--
你想要什么都可以
Whatever you need, whatever you want.
什么都不需要
That won't be necessary.
当我回家的时候  我会做个好公民
When I'm back home, I'm a saint.
甚至连红灯都不会闯
I'm not even jaywalking.
奥斯贝托  别忘了
Osberto. don't forget.
奥斯贝托
Osberto.
一旦斯科菲尔德从隧道出来  他就死定了
Scofield steps outside that tunnel, he's a dead man.
我想我们有两条路
Far as I can tell, we have two options.
要么让萨米入伙
We can invite Sammy on the escape...
见你的鬼去吧！
He can go to hell.
所以我们只能选择另一条路
Which brings us to option number two.
你不会和萨米是一伙的吧
You wouldn't last a second in there with Sammy.
那你呢
Would you?
我想我们必须出去
Then I guess we'll just have to outsource.
我觉得对不住那个伙计
I felt sorry for the guy,
但是你必须要应战
But you don't chicken-foot an ex-delta force
每个人都有求生的欲望
And expect to make it out alive.
你赢了  像恰克·诺里斯一样
You're delta force? like Chuck Norris?
诺里斯?  他在这里的话也不一定能赢
Norris? he wouldn't have made it through boot camp.
等我一下
Excuse me a second.
我看你交到新朋友了
I see you're making friends.
一旦你赢了比赛
Hey, once you get the hang of it,
这里就不再乏味了
This place ain't so rough.
是的  很糟
Yeah. too bad.
什么很糟
Too bad what?
你是对的
You were right. we got
我们有个计划  不过如果你不懂规矩
A little plan going on. but, you know, if you're putting down roots...
不  不  你说...
No, no. you were saying...?
我们要在48小时内设法逃离这里
We're supposed to be out of here in 48 hours.
不是和斯科菲尔德一起吧
Not through Scofield.
你听见刚才的喊话了吧
You heard the town crier.
那个聪明仔的一条命也就值一箱酒
College boy's life is barely worth a case of booze.
别转移话题
Hence our current conversation.
我知道你昨天是怎么赢的
I know how you got your cherry yesterday,
你在你绑手的带子上涂了丙酮
Daubing your wraps in acetone,
捂住那家伙直到窒息而死
Smothering the guy until he passed out from the fumes.
你若如法炮制弄死萨米  你就能跟我们走
You do the same thing to Sammy, and you're in.
向萨米挑战
Chicken-foot Sammy?
Chicken-foot Sammy.
全靠你了  老大
It's all riding on you, champ.
请拿好
Here you get it.
谢谢
Thank you.
不会耽误很久的
This shouldn't take long.
你在做什么
What are you getting?
-做准备  -什么准备?
Supplies. for?
我不想打无准备之仗
I don't want to get caught flat-footed again.
你知道是什么意思吗
You know no.what that means?
这些人显然有他们的计划
Well, these people obviously have a plan.
我们也要有一个计划
We're gonna need one, too.
那计划包括营救詹姆斯吗
Does that plan include screwing over James?
那家伙叫詹姆斯还是米勒?
Is it James or gary Miller?
无论他叫什么
Whatever his name is, there's a part of me
我不相信他会为他们卖命
That doesn't want to believe he works for them...
因为
Cause he's
我爱这个男人
The man I loved,
这个男人因为我才进的监狱
The man who went to prison for me,
我的第一次巴黎之旅就是和这个男人一起
The man who was going to take me to my first trip to paris.
我不能背叛他
I haven't turned my back to that man.
你能告诉我他是否还好
Do I have your word that he's gonna be all right?
是的  上车吧
Yeah. now get in.
你说明白点
Do I have your word?!
我说了他很好
Yeah, you got my word.
现在可以上车了
Now get in.
Ed 我们马上能见面了  销售非常好!
Ed, we'll be in contact soon. Sales are through the roof!
希望你还在忙你那块  格雷发
Hope you're working on your putting...Gary
你知道我刚才发现了什么?
You know what st found out?
"苏克雷"的意思就是"糖"
That "Sucre" means "sugar."
是的
Yeah.
所以每次我说到你的名字
So every time I say your name,
我就用"糖"代替
I'm calling you "sugar."
明白
Basically.
我喜欢这么叫
I like that.
我没有搞到很多消息
Look, I don't have a lot of information.
对你来说很好  不是吗
Which, I guess, that's good ws for you, right?
你能详细说下吗
You care to elaborate?
林肯没有什么行动
Lincoln isn't cooking anything up.
他还是在计划拿惠斯勒交换lj
He's still planning on exchanging Whistler for lj.
他没提过什么别的计划
He hasn't been talking about running any games.
昨晚他也没什么特别的行动吗
And did he become an eagle scout last night, too?
小姐  他得到了消息  他知道只能这样
Lady, he got the message. he knows he doest have
他决定就这么行动
A choice, he has to play it straight.
我来这里告诉你这些
Look, I could have come up here and made something up
只是想捞点钱  但是
Just to get paid, but...
我对你没有别的企图
I'm not trying to get on your bad side either.
你知道么
You know what?
我相信你
I believe you.
如果有什么进展我再联系你
So, I'll call you if anything comes up.
当我是什么  不要脸的妓女?
Whoa, whoa! what am i, a toothless crack whore?
坐下
Sit down.
我会兑现承诺
I keep my promises.
我上面的人
The people I work for, they don't like
他们不在乎钞票  他们有的是钱
To deal in greenbacks; it's just too bulky.
银行的支票  直接兑换现金
Cashier's check payable to cash. same thing.
事成以后还有一半
Half now and half when you're done.
甜心  盯紧点
Keep your ears open, sugar.
阿历克斯  加把劲
Alex, come on!
-用力  -我在用力
Hold it steady! I am! I am!
我需要点帮助
I'm gonna need a little help here!
加油
Come on.
快好了  我知道可以的
I got it. I said I got it.
这个小部件能承受所有的重量吗
Thittle piece of metal's gonna hold all this weight?
好了
All right,
我松手了
Let go, let go.
我们还需要多少个撑钉
So, how many more are we gonna need
才能上去?
Before we get to the top?
或许20个吧
20 maybe.
这也就是让我们能去禁入区  然后呢?
That gets us to no-man's land. then what?
有直升机当然更好啦
Helicopter'd be nice.
我本可以杀了你
I was supposed to kill you.
所以你就不是什么渔夫
Oh, so you're not a fisherman?
他们威胁要追杀我全家
They threatened to come after my family
除非我杀了你  跳上直升机
If I didn't kill you and jump on that helicopter,
但是我还是没有那么做
But I didn't.
这么说我还该感激你
I'm so grateful.
那你的家人怎么样了?
So what happened to your family?
不知道  从这里出去后或许就能知道了
I don't know. maybe I'll find out if we ever get out of here.
这个世界很疯狂  不是吗？
Well, it's a crazy world, isn't it?
我们都会赞同这点的
We all agreen that.
我们还有很多事要做
And we have a lot of work to do.
该死的勒齐哪去了?
Where the hell is Lechero?
-事情都办妥了?  -什么?
Is everything set? huh?
事情都办妥了?
Is everything set?
是的  没有问题
Yeah, noblemo.
抱歉  先生
Excuse me, sir.
如果需要鸡爪是不是来找你?
Do we come to you if we need the chicken foot?
还穿虎纹裤子
Tiger pants.
你和谁过不去?
Who you got a beef with?
我不知道他的名字  是个加勒比海的家伙
I don't know his name. some caribbean guy.
之前偷了我的皮夹子
Stole my wallet a while back.
你最好想想清楚
Better think long and hard
再开口  听到吗?
Before you say another word, eh?
他留着撇小胡子
He's got this fruity little mustache
穿了件奇丑无比的背心
And this ly-ass vest.
接着  算我求你了
Please, I'm beggin' ya.
15分钟后  场子里见
In the ring. 15 minutes.
我从没有想过我会这么说
I never thought I'd say this,
布拉德  但是我很欣赏你
But I envy you, Brad. I've wanted
我打见到那小子起  就想手刃了他
To shank that little calypso kid
我虽然不是天生暴力
Ever since I first met him. I'm not a violent guy by nature,
但是如果有人逼我太甚的话...
But if a man makes me walk around in my grunts for two days...
很不错  别折磨他太久  早点干掉
Yeah, that's great. just don't take too long to finish him off, okay?
他死的越快  我们也可以快些逃出去
The sooner he's dead, the sooner we can get on the escape.
说定了  我也算一个
No games. I'm in.
算你一个
You're in.
-不  不  -怎么了？
No, no, no. what's wrong?
我们必须取消那场格斗
We got to call off the fight.
不  这根本不可能
No, that's an impossibility.
不  不
No, no, no,
你根本不明白
You don't understand!
这附近应该还有丙酮的
There's got to be more acetone around here.
你说到点子上了  没有丙酮
No, that's it! I can't go against
我去直面萨米的话  那死定了
Sammy straight up! I'm a dead man!
你要是不杀了他  我们都玩完
If you don't kill him, we are all dead.
这样的邻舍可不咋地
This isn't the best neighborhood.
我还去过更糟的
I've been in a lot worse.
跟紧点就是了
Just stick close.
奥斯贝托?
Osberto?
是的
Si.
你想做交易吗？
You want to do this?
现钞准备好了?
iene el dinero?
是的  我准备好了
Yeah, yeah, I got it.
钱在哪里？（西班牙语）
onde esta?
钱在哪里？
"where is the money?"
我想看货
I want to see the product.
先付钱（西班牙语）
Primero el dinero.
先付钱
"money first."
我先看货
Show me the stuff.
先付钱!
El dinero!
林肯求你了  我们离开这吧
Lincoln, please, let's get out of here.
告诉他别再浪费我的时间
Tell him to stop wasting my time.
不行
No.
和他说
Tell him.
我的天啊!
Oh, my god!
威力够大吗？
Big? it's grande?
是的
Si.
问他如何遥控引爆
Ask him how do I trigger it by remote.
就爆了
Boom.
拨号1-1 然后按发送键
"dial one-one, send."
1-1 然后发送键?
One-one, send?
再见
Adios.
祝你好运
Buena suerte.
你为什么不告诉我你要买个炸弹?
Why didn't you tell me you were gonna buy a bomb?
说了的话  你怎么也不会来了
You never d have come otherwise.
这玩意当锯子不错
We need that saw.
你们知道吗
You know, uh,
我是名渔夫
I am a fisherman.
我  或许我只是
I am. I'm just maybe
被关注的超过本身多了些
A little bit more connected than I've let on.
我觉得这东西能起作用
I think this is gonna work.
是的
Yeah.
你知道  我经营租赁  正如我说的那样
You know, I run charters, just like I said...
都好几年了
I have for years.
然后某一天  那个婊子格雷琴她问我
Then one day, that brunette, Gretchen well, she asked me
是否愿意和她合作发财
If I wanted to be exclusive to her corporation, right?
她开的价不低
And, uh, well, with the money she was offering,
我很清楚  她肯定不是为了
I had a pretty good idea she wasn't
捕鲑鱼这么简单
Just trawling for salmon.
这么说  你们之间还发生过些事情
So you two have history.
是的
Yeah. and she's
她绝对是我此生的梦魇
Been an absolute nightmare in my life
从第一个工作开始
Ever since that first job.
阿历克斯  我需要一个楔子
Alex, I need a wedge.
楔子
Wedge.
如你们所见  我曾经把他们带到他们想去的地方
Look, I took 'em where they wanted me to take 'em.
我得弄明白这些坐标
I have to figure outhese coordinates
我必须把他们再带到那去
And I have to take them back there.
不要再为难你自己了
Quit embarrassing yourself.
什么?
What?
我们不是2只你试图在鸡笼里面捡起的小鸡
We're not two chicks at a bar you're trying to pick up.
你觉得呢?
This?
你为组织工作
No. all right, good. you work for the company.
当你从这里出去的时候
And when you break out of here, you're gonna do whatever
你就会做组织要你做的一切
The company asks you to do,
-没有了  -他们利用我
Period. well, they're using me
正如他们利用你一样
Just like they're g you.
很好  我很荣幸能和你分享这样的经历
Good, I'm glad you shared that with me.
你为什么不回去工作?  这个建议听起来怎么样?
So why don't we go back to work? how's that sound?
让那些笨蛋自己去争夺他们想要的一切吧
Let those idiots chickenfoot themselves all they want, huh?
不过如果有人想给我们一个鸡爪...
But if one of them tries to use it on us...
你不需要和那个人决斗
You don't have to fight that guy.
这是辞别之旅
It's my farewell tour.
剩下的几块质量不太好
The rest of those pieces are no good.
我们需要那些工具  迈克
We're going to need those tools, Michael.
我觉得我们只能等待了
I guess we'll just have to wait.
你的那本书--
That book of yours-- it's just a bunch
它里面只是一堆坐标  是吗
Of coordinates in there, right?
那些坐标穿插在其他的东西里面
Among other things.
那你肯定不会介意我看看
So you wouldn't mind.
只是一串数字和日期
It's just a bunch of, uh, numbers and dates.
"门"
"gate."
"门网公司"
Gate netting company.
是我租借渔网的地方
That's where I rent my trammels.
"逃窜"
"stampede."
那是我好友的"Cape islander"(一种渔船)
That's my buddy's cape islander.
现在这对我们来说很重要吗
And this is important to us how?
很重要  因为它们我被误会了
It's important because I'm being accused
而且我不想
Of being someone I'm not. and I don't want
斯科菲尔德在将来要离开的时候抛弃我
Scofield ditching me
他没有抛弃任何人
Once it's time to leave... he's not ditching anybody.
如果他能摆脱任何人
If he could have gotten rid of anybody,
他也会摆脱我
He would have gotten rid of me.
如果他试图离开这个城市
And if he tries to leave the city
他知道我们会在他离开之前检举他
He knows that we're gonna turn him in before he gets out
我上楼去找勒齐和他的工具
Of the city. I'm going upstairs to find Lechero and his equipment.
我和阿历克斯一起
I'm with Alex.
你介意吗
Do you mind?
听起来上面有人
Sounds like someone's up there.
如果是勒齐在上面陷入困境
If Lechero gets stranded up there,
我们现在不能离开这里
We're not getting out of here.
那么当你觉得安全的时候
So when you think it's safe,
或者...
Or it feels like
它确实变得安全的时候  我们就上去
It's safe, we got to go, we got to go up.
几个月来我们一直在说要挑战萨米
We've been talking about chickenfooting Sammy for months.
没人有那个勇气
No one had the courage.
你有油漆稀释剂吗
Do you have any paint thinner?
油漆稀释剂?
Paint thinner?
鞋油
Shoe polish,
打火机油  或者胶水?
Lighter fluid, glue?
找到你了  冠军
There you are, champ.
时间到了  重跺他的脸吧  布拉德!
It's time. stomp his face, Brad!
你知道  这整个就是误会
You know, this has all been one big misunderstanding.
我没有谈论萨米
I wasn't talking about Sammy.
我谈论的是...是他!
It was... that's him.
他才是我谈论的那个人
That's the guy I was talking about.
我可没看见他有"恶心的胡子"
Yeah, I don't see no "fruity moustache,"
而且那"丑陋的汗衫"在哪  布拉德?
And where's his "ugly-ass vest," Brad?
不必担心  你有真正的机会赢了这局
Don't worry, you stand a real chance of winning this one.
你不能整天这样躲着外面
You cannot just hide out all day.
我还能做什么?
What else can I do, huh?
我残酷的统治了这些人一年
I've ruledhese men for a year with blood.
你不知道他们多么渴望干掉老大
You don't think those men want to take the head of the man
无论如何
Who wore the crown? be that as it may,
贝里克就要把他的头输给萨米了
Bellick is about to lose his head to Sammy.
你可能不想听这些
You may not want to hear this,
一旦这事发生  我们都十分清楚
But once that happens, we are both very much
斯科菲尔德就会好奇
Aware that Scofield is gonna start
你到底在哪里
Getting curious about where the hell you are.
他就会爬出他的洞
He's going to come crawling out of his hole
正好到萨米的手下
And right into Sammy's arms,
然后他和我们的越狱大计
And then he and our escape
就永远消失了
Are gone forever.
贝里克
Bellick, Bellick, Bellick,
Bellick, Bellick, Bellick, Bellick, Bellick,
贝里克
Bellick, Bellick, Bellick,
Bellick, Bellick, Bellick, Bellick...
等等  我们拿了工具直接回来
Wait. we get the tools and we come straight back.
跟上
Come on
嘿
Hey.
你们想要看看决斗吗
You guys want to watch the fight?
颤抖吧
You know, chill out.
我会给你拿瓶啤酒
I'll get you a beer.
你喜欢那样?
You like that?
停下!
Stop it.
斯科菲尔德!
Scofield!
斯科菲尔德在这里
Scofield's in there.
-锁上了  -开门
It's locked. open the door.
我没有密码
I don't have the combination.
我说...
I said...
打开门!
Open it now.
开啊
Do it.
不行
We can't.
现在打开!
Open it now.
我没有密码
I don't have the combination.
我手上有你的人
I've got your man out here.
如果你们不开门的话
If you don't open the door,
他就要付出代价
He's the one who's going to pay the price.
他得活着!
I need him alive!
你看过那些人  你难道不知道他们打算干什么?
You saw those guys. what do you think they've got planned?
你们正在挑战我的耐心
All of you is trying my patience.
你有什么建议  阿历克斯?
What do you suggest, Alex?
我们得准备好
Let's be ready for them.
时间到了
Time's up.
你还想再挨一下吗
You want another one?
那你得坚强点
Then you better be persuasive.
迈克
Michael.
别开门!
Don't open the door!
他有枪!
He's got a gu...!
-你不打算和我解释一下吗?  -不
Are you going to tell me what it's for? no.
你怕我告诉詹姆斯?
Because you think I might tell James?
因为你没必要知道
Because you don't need to know.
嗨
Hey.
不会有事的
It's going to be all right.
-怎么样?  -很好  我说了她想听到的话
How'd it go? good. I told her what she wanted to hear,
就象你事先告诉我的那样
Just like you told me.
-是吗?  -对
That it? yeah.
那好  听着  我要你给她打电话
Cool. listen, I want you to call her up,
告诉她你这有些情报
Tell her you've got some information.
一定要让她来接你  然后上她的车  明白了?
Make sure she picks you up, and get in the car, all right?
好的  没什么问题吧?
Okay. is everything okay?
没有  为什么这么问?
Yeah. why?
她看起来很不安
She looks upset.
我回头给你电话
I'll call you later.
迈克  我找到一个我们能用得上的东西
Got something down here we can use, Michael.
如果他们从那扇门进来
If they come through that door...
你就在这里给他们致命打击
You hit 'em right here.
快拿着
Go ahead, take it.
拿着!
Go ahead.
这东西能穿透心脏
It'll puncture the heart.
你把斯科菲尔德藏在
You were hiding
你房间里了?
Scofield in your room?
你看看  权力已经让你失去理智
Look at you-- the power make you mad already.
来吧  诺曼  我们走
Come along, Norman.
我们走
Let's go.
什么事情这么着急?
What is so urgent?
林肯买了一把枪
Lincoln bought a gun.
我...  我问他打算用来干什么
I... I asked him what he planned on doing with it,
他没有回答我
But he wouldn't answer.
我觉得...  我想我也许应该告诉你
So I just... I just thought you might want to know.
如果有什么变化我再向你报告  好吗?
If anything changes, I'll get back to you, okay?
你知道吗  那天你和林肯
You ow, the other day
在大堂那吵了起来
When you and lincoln had your little spat in the lobby
我看你撕心裂肺地
And you-- all distraught and jilted--
跑到对面街的酒吧里
Went across the street to the bar,
明眼人一看就知道你们在演戏
A cynic might think that was staged.
我的眼睛就挺亮的  宝贝
I'm a cynic, sugar.
是你想晕了头  宝贝
You're high, sugar.
不过演得还是挺逼真的  差点把我也给蒙了
If it's any comfort, you guys almost pulled it off.
什么波多黎各人啦  大猩猩啦
The puerto rican and the gorilla--
还真地让我为你们揪心了一会儿
You really had me scrambling there for a minute.
如果你不需要我的帮助就算了  我退出!
Hey, if you don't want my help, fine, I'm out, okay?
我只不过是根据我给你
It's a little thing called a tracing number--
那张支票的号码顺藤摸瓜而已
On the check I gave you.
很显然  那天你没把
Apparently your extensive expertise
你在银行方面丰富的专业知识
In banking
带在身上
Failed you that day.
你迫不及待地把两万五美金
You promptly wired all 25 k
全部转给了
To maricruz delgado
芝加哥的玛丽克鲁兹·德尔加多
In chicago
那个娇弱的令人怜爱的
At 123 please don't hurt me lane.
我发誓  如果她有什么三长两短...
I swear to god, if something happens to her...
那又怎么样!
If what?!
说呀  王八蛋!
What, jackass?!
你还是老老实实回去
You're going to go back there and you're going to get me
给我弄一些真正的情报
Some real information,
要不然玛丽克鲁兹就会脑袋搬家!
Or Maricruz and her head are going to part ways.
从我的车里滚出去!
Get out of my car.
现在就滚!
Now.
嗨  布兰科
Hey, Blanco.
你的好兄弟勒齐来了
I got your good buddy Lechero here.
你干吗不用暗号敲门  好让他知道是你来了
Why don't you give it the secret knock so he knows it's you, huh?
密码
The combination.
你怎么会认为我知道密码呢?
What makes you think I have the combination?
乖乖照他说的做  明白吗?
Just do what he says. huh?
你究竟要拿这把小玩意威胁我多少次?
How many times you gonna pull that little thing out?
我想多少次就多少次  只要我觉得有必要
As many times as I feel necessary.
因为它让你觉得你很强大  对吗?
What, you think it make you look strong?
其实虚张声势只会让你显得更加脆弱
All it does is magnify your weakness.
真可笑  现在我感觉很好
Funny, I'm feeling pretty
一切尽在掌握!
Secu right about now.
快把密码交出来  我们不会再问你一次
Now, the combination, old man. we're not asking again.
萨米!
Sammy!
我要开门啦!
I'm opening the door.
迈克  别开!
Michael, do not open the...
把家伙放下!
Drop 'em!
我说把家伙放下!
Drop them, I sai
走!
Now move!
你打算和他一起逃走?
You're escaping with him?
我本来想把一切都告诉你的
I was gonna tell you all about this, bredda.
但你就是没开口  对吗?
It just never camep, eh?
都拿去吧
Take it.
都是你的了
It's yours.
隧道
The tunnel,
逃跑计划  所有的
The escape plan, everything.
我们可以一起逃走
We can go together.
我会拿走一切
I'm taking everything you t.
不过你哪也别想去
But you ain't going nowhere.
你们打算如何完成这个洞?
How you finishing up this hole?
答应我带惠斯勒一起走
Promise me you'll take Whistler with you.
你在要求我吗?
You making demands on me?
是吗?
Hu
我知道
I understand...
为什么你会杀了我
Why you're going to kill me,
但他没做错什么
But he's done nothing wrong.
我会告诉你你想知道的一切
I'll tell you everything you need to know,
只要你把他带上
Just take him with you.
你需要他
You need him.
整个计划都是他想出来的
He's the only one who figured this one out.
别担心  我会照顾好你朋友的
Don't you worry, I'll take care of yoriend.
那好
All right.
首先  你们要继续一边前进
First, you need to keep building braces
一边做支撑物支撑隧道
To support the tunnel as you go.
怎么做?
How you do that?
惠斯勒会教你们
Whistler can show you how.
看起来你们
Look like you just
用这些箱子做了些木框
Make some wood squares from these boxes here.
我说了
Like I said,
惠斯勒会教你们
Whistler can show you.
离地面还有多远?
How much further to the surface?
很近了
Not far.
不会超过10英尺
Can't be more than ten feet.
真不赖啊  布兰科
Impressive, Blanco.
真遗憾你不能享用它了
Too bad you won't be around to enjoy it.
这样的情况对我们有多大影响?
How long is this going to set us back?
如果警戒塔上的哨兵
What's gonna set us back is if the tower guards are looking at
看见荒地里塌下去一个大洞就糟了
A giant sinkhole out in no man's land.
迈克?
Michael?
没事
We're good.
对
Yeah.
还好没事
We're good.
重新开工
Back in business.
我加入
I'm in.
加入什么?  你想被他们打死吗?
For what, getting your ass kicked?
我加入他们  或者到屋顶上把一切都嚷出来
I'm in or I shout it from the rooftops.
你最好也一块加入
You're in, champ.
你要待在这
Okay, you need to stay here.
我要去取点东西
I got to get something, all right?
别走开
Don't move.
从这里你能自己回家吗?
Can you get home from here?
可以  我家就隔了两个街区
Yeah, I'm two blocks away.
如果他不带你走  我带你走
If he doesn't take you, I will.
拿着
Here.
用这个
Use this.
谢谢
Thanks.
好好擦擦  就在那
Right there.
你总是要我证明
You know, for all the times you wanted me
自己是个渔夫
To prove I was a fisherman,
其实我也该问问你是否真地是个工程师
I should have been asking if you were a real engineer.
我们两个其中一个本来应该被塌方埋葬的
That could've been one of us buried down there.
下次我会做得更好的
I'll do bett next time.
我下去修整一下那些支撑物
I'm gonna go back down and try to salvage some of those braces.
好  我和你一起去
Yeah, I'll go with you.
这种事总是这么困难的
Never gets any easier.
斯科菲尔德  有人来探视你
Scofield, visita.
我把在索纳三年做小工的钱都攒起来了
All the side jobs I do at Sona for three years. I save all of my money.
一共是173美金
It's $173.
如果你真地要走  这些钱都给你
If you're really leaving, it's yours.
把我也带上吧
Take me with you.
求你了
Please?
我再也不想在这待了
I don't want to be here anymore.
你还是不要掺和进来
You don't want any part of this.
你有计划了吗?  还是我们又回到了起点?
You got a plan or are we back to square one?
-我有计划了  -好  我在外面也安排好了
I have a plan. good, 'cause I got something cooking on tutside.
这次我可不想再碰壁了
I ain't walking into a buzzsaw again.
和里面那些野兽们相处得怎么样?
How you dealing with the animals in here?
实际上这里越来越有家的感觉了
Actually, it's starting to feel like home.
惠斯勒还在假扮渔夫  就这样?
Whistler still pretending he's a fisherman and all this?
-怎么了?  -索菲亚在他的公寓里发现一本护照
Why? Sofia found a passport in one of the apartments he kept.
上面的名字是格雷·米勒
Name's Gary Miller.
我很吃惊  这家伙是个骗子
I'm shocked. guy's a fraud, michael.
据我所知  史高戴尔根本没有鱼
As far as I know, there ain't fish in Scottsdale.
他不是渔夫  那他是干什么的?
Well, if he's not a fisherman... what is he?